{
  "reference_number": "7462",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "We should be aiming to reach net zero earlier than 2050."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "I think it is a good idea to have 5 year targets, though we should aim to communicate where we stand in reaching these goals\n\n beyond an annual report- stats should be readily available year round"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "No, unless the goal is to be more ambitious."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We need to hold everyone accountable, in order for New Zealand to reduce its collective output of emissions, there should be\n\nallocated allowances across the country. Why have we not structured a framework that requires individuals or companies, institutions\nof education etc to record their emission outputs, and place a tax on any over expenditures. We also need to place a huge emphasis\n\non environmental education. We cannot expect these goals to be met when the definition of sustainability is not yet agreed upon or\neven common knowledge, so how are we suppose to work towards such an ambiguous idea."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "These are all post climate change adaptations, yes we should be preparing for future implications of such issues as weather\n\nextremities, though there is no mention of preventative adaptation. We should be acknowledging how we can alter our lifestyles in\norder to reduce the future effects of Climate Change."
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We need to seriously consider that the vast majority of short lived gasses are coming from NZ agriculture. The consultation held on\n\nthe 4th July in Wellington referenced 'the evolution of technology' a lot and seemed to rely on this as our saviour. Sure, there will be\ncleaner alternatives that can replace the comforts embedded into our current lifestyles - such as the electric car. This will be huge for\nreducing the amount of carbon emission if we are to look at the ecological running cost of cars. It does not however take into\n\nconsideration the embodied emissions of a cars production, and how their accessibility (of having extremely low running costs) will\nimpact the way we use vehicles. It is likely that due to their availability, the amount of cars on the road will increase, along with their\n\nuse. So we've got to consider the surrounding infrastructure around alternative technologies and how they may contribute further\nunsustainable habits.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
